The story of an orphan who would be king.
Mufasa: The Lion King is a adventure, family,
animation film directed by Barry Jenkins.
Mufasa, a cub lost and alone, meets a sympathetic lion
named Taka, the heir to a royal bloodline.
The chance meeting sets in motion an expansive journey of a
group of misfits searching for their destiny.
Mufasa (voice), played by Aaron Pierre.
Taka (voice), played by Kelvin Harrison, Jr..
Sarabi (voice), played by Tiffany Boone.
Young Rafiki (voice), played by Kagiso Lediga.
Zazu (voice), played by Preston Nyman.
Kiara (voice), played by Blue Ivy Carter.
Mufasa: The Lion King is a 2024 American musical drama
film produced by Walt Disney Pictures.
The photorealistically animated film serves as both a prequel and sequel to The
Lion King (2019), which itself is a remake of the 1994 animated film.
Directed by Barry Jenkins from a screenplay written by Jeff Nathanson, the film's cast includes Seth Rogen, Billy Eichner, Donald Glover, Beyoncé Knowles-Carter, and John Kani reprising their roles from the
remake; new cast members include Aaron Pierre, Kelvin Harrison Jr., Tiffany Boone, Mads Mikkelsen, Thandiwe Newton, Lennie James, Anika Noni Rose, and Blue Ivy Carter in her feature film debut.
It features Rafiki recounting to Simba and Nala's cub, Kiara, the history of Mufasa, including how he first met Scar and other allies,
his battle against a renegade pride of white lions, and the journey that led him to become King of the Pride Lands.
Development on a prequel to The Lion King was confirmed in September 2020, with
Jenkins attached to direct and Nathanson finishing a draft of the script.
Pierre and Harrison were announced as the voice cast in August 2021,
followed by further casting between September 2022 and April 2024.
The film was officially announced when its official title was revealed
in September 2022 at the 2022 D23 Expo announcement.
Production on the film slowed down in July 2023
due to the 2023 SAG-AFTRA strike.
The film is dedicated to James Earl Jones, the voice of Mufasa in the 1994 film and remake, who died three months
before the film's release; as a tribute, his voice is heard briefly during the opening titles.
Mufasa: The Lion King premiered on December 9, 2024, at the Dolby Theatre in Los Angeles, and was
distributed in the United States by Walt Disney Studios Motion Pictures on December 20.
The film received mixed reviews from critics and grossed $723
million, making it the sixth-highest-grossing film of 2024.
The film explores themes of friendship, paradise, lion, musical, prequel.